In 1982, the fruits of a partnership between
1982年，索尼和飞利浦之间成功的合作成果
Sony and Philips were released to the music-loving public,
向喜爱音乐的公众发布了
The Compact Disc, or CD, was unveiled as the first consumer digital audio format.
激光唱片(CD)是第一个面向消费者的数码音频介质
These 12 cm discs could store up to 74 minutes of perfect quality digital audio,
12厘米的光盘能存储多达74分钟的高质量数码音频
注：后来有80分钟的音频CD，因为制造商将轨道间的间隙给缩短了
J. Hendrix的Electric Ladyland长75分钟 1986初版为双CD 1990再版为单CD
and as was famously demonstrated many times over, were immune from liquid damage,
而且多方证实，它能免疫液体伤害，有些微划伤也无碍
could withstand significant scratching, and could be played without wearing them down
Homer：你小子小时候把我多少张盘都划上道子了，结果你现在看成宝了。
而且理论上，还可以没有磨损地播放无限次
for a theoretically infinite number of times.
That’s because, unlike all previous sound formats where
这是因为，不像以往的介质，将声音编码成
sound is encoded as an analog impression of the sound wave on plastic discs or magnetic tape,
模拟的声波信号，再将其录在黑胶或磁带上那样
the sound on a CD is encoded as a series of samples,
录在CD上的声音信息实际上是一系列采样
which function as a set of instructions on how to recreate the sound.
也就是用来重放声音的一系列指令
The Compact Disc was a BIG FREAKING DEAL in many ways!
在任何方面，激光唱片都很重要
It represented a giant leap in convenience for the consumer,
他体现了在消费级的高品质录音
quality of the recorded sound, and in raw data storage capacity.
以及原始数据存储方面的巨大进步
That last bit wouldn’t be too relevant to the computing industry for some time,
后者在CD推出后的一段时间内都没有在计算机领域中体现
注：规定CD-ROM标准的黄皮书在1988年出品，规定音频CD标准的红皮书在1980年出品
but it solved the central problem of digital sound--
但是它还是解决了数码音频技术的核心问题
needing a, for the time, absurdly massive amount of raw data,
它提供了很大的存储空间，来存储在当年看来大到离谱的数据
Before we get too far into the specifics of the Compact Disc,
在我们开始介绍CD的具体细节前
it’s time to dig a little deeper into how digital sound actually works.
我们花亿些时间来介绍一下数码音频工作的具体原理
Recall from my last video that an analog-to-digital converter
话说上回，我提到模数转换器是按照特定的采样频率
is taking instantaneous samples of the analog signal at a specific sampling frequency,
采样瞬时的模拟声音信号
Then, a DAC can recreate the original analog signal with only those samples.
然后数模转换器根据采样，重新生成原先的模拟信号
Well, a lot of people think that this can’t possibly work to recreate
然而，很多人认为这种方式不能完全
all the detail in the original analog sound wave.
还原原先模拟信号的每一个细节
But thanks to mathematics, we know that it can, and does.
但万恶的数学又一次打了我们的脸，实际上是可以的
It’s time to explore the Nyquist-Shannon sampling theorem.
现在我们来了解一下采样原理
This theorem was co-discovered by E.T.Whittaker and Vladimir Kotelnikov.
该定理由这两个人发现
So it is also, but less commonly, referred to as the...
所以说，该定理也被称为......
Anyway, Harry Nyquist and Claude Shannon, along with the other two,
无论如何，奈奎斯特和香农，以及那两个人
discovered that a band-limited signal, that means a signal which does not contain
均注意到了被截频的信号，也就是不包含
frequency above a certain limit, can be perfectly described and perfectly reconstructed
高于某种频率的信号，只要采样率为原信号最高频率的两倍
by taking instantaneous samples at twice the rate of the frequency limit,
就可以被完美地描述（编码）并复现
This gets a little complicated, so I’m going to explain it as best as I can,
听上去很复杂，所以我尽力来解释
Our hearing itself is bandlimited. Though frequencies exist in nature above 20,000 hertz,
我们的听力本身就是有带宽限制的，尽管自然界中有高于
人类听力范围
our ears cannot detect anything above that frequency. Some people claim they can but,
20kHz的信号，但我们是无法听到的。先不管那些声称能
well, most people rapidly lose their hearing at those high frequencies as they age,
听见的人，大多数人随年龄增长而损失对高频声音的听力
and I’m talking like as they leave childhood, so let’s just not go there.
真的过于简化了！
那时他们肯定不是小朋友啦，所以我们不考虑了
With the knowledge that anything above 20,000 hertz will just not be audible,
地球人都知道，超过20kHz的声音我们就听不到了
we can therefore capture all of the audio we can hear
所以我们仅需捕获低于20kHz的声音就可以了
by only recording sounds below 20 kilohertz.
Passing an analog input through what’s called a low-pass filter
将模拟信号经过低通滤波器处理后
will eliminate any frequencies above a specified point.
高于某个频率的信号就被截断了
There’s no sense in recording sounds we can’t hear, so we can use
毕竟录制我们听不到的信号就是浪费
a low-pass filter to eliminate frequency components above 20 kilohertz.
所以我们拿个低通滤波器截下信号就好了
And we end up with a signal that represents all that we can hear.
最终获得的信号，也就是我们能听到的所有信号了
And is, importantly, band-limited.
当然，更重要的是，信号的带宽被限制了
For now, we’re going to assume this can work perfectly,
从现在开始，我们假设刚才这套十分理想
so we’ll say that any signals above 20 kHz cannot pass through the low pass filter.
也就是说，所有高于20kHz频率的信号无法通过低通滤波器
Nyquist-Shannon tells us that by sampling at a rate of 40 kilohertz,
由采样原理知，当我们的采样率为40kHz时
we can capture all the detail possible in this newly band-limited signal.
我们可以采集到该截过频信号的详细信息
That may sound a little unintuitive, but let’s explain why it’s true.
听上去很反直觉，不过我来解释一下这是为什么
When you have a band-limited signal, certain types of sounds get reduced
一个带宽受限的信号可以用一堆正弦波的谐波来表示
to a representation of themselves made as a sum of sine wave harmonics.
Fourier transformation, which is another complicated math subject
由傅里叶变换（一会就知道有多腻味人的复杂数学知识）可知
that will rear its ugly head a little later, means that we can
我们可以用一大堆正弦波的谐波表示任何波形
represent any waveform as a sum of sine wave harmonics.
The most classic illustration of this is a square wave.
最经典的示例就是方波了
A true square wave looks like this, but to actually reproduce this signal
理想方波如上，但要重现方波信号的话，需要接近无限的带宽
would require near infinite bandwidth. And I know what you’re saying, that seems silly.
当然，我早猜到你们会说：嘛玩意？
This is just a rapid hard cut in and out of a signal.
这就是快速地变换高低电平的信号啊
Like flipping a light switch on and off, Ehh, that’s true.
就像开关灯一样啊。好吧，你没说错
But if we could produce this signal, then this vertical piece,
但要重现信号的话，单就垂直部分
which represents an instantaneous increase in amplitude,
也就是在无限小的时间内快速抬升电平的部分
would require a frequency response that’s ridiculously high.
就需要快到不得了的高频率回复
See if we can make that instantaneous shift from low to high intensity,
你看啊，我们要是能在无限小的时间内将电平由低变高
then we must be able to produce the same shift downward in the same amount of time,
我们也必须能在同样无限小的时间内拉下电平
which is no time at all if it truly is instantaneous.
真要是无限小的话，那就是没有时间了
To do that would require infinite bandwidth, that’s more than we have to play with.
相对应的，就得是无限大的带宽，我们可处理不了
So when this signal is passed through a low-pass filter of 20 kilohertz, it comes out like this.
当信号经过低通滤波器截到20kHz后，结果如右
This is the sum of harmonics that would create this square wave via a fourier transform,
这就是一堆正弦波通过傅立叶变换生成的类似方波的谐波
but the highest frequency harmonic possible is 20 kilohertz.
谐波的最高频率为20kHz
Because we’ve placed a bandlimit on the input,
由于我们在输入信号时限制信号频率了
we’re dealing with nothing but sine waves now, piled on top of each other.
我们仅需只需处理一堆叠在一起的正弦波信号了
We are constructing any other waveforms as a sum of sine wave harmonics,
我们将其他的波形都可视为一系列正弦波的谐波
and this explains why the Nyquist-Shannon theorem holds true.
这就解释了采样原理的正确性
If the sample goes from the lowest possible to the highest possible value and back,
若采样从最低值到最高值后，又回到最低值
the only waveform that can hit those three samples is
能经过着三个采样点的，只能是奈奎斯特频率为20kHz的正弦波
奈奎斯特频率：为防止信号混叠需要定义最小采样频率，在这理解为之前说的最高频率吧
SuperBart: 学计算机的学不学这堆玩意啊？
a sine wave at the Nyquist frequency of 20 kilohertz.
超级完美的正弦波(bushi
We can’t describe any frequencies higher than 20 kilohertz,
我们不能获得高于20kHz的信号
but just two samples per cycle is enough to define our highest possible frequency.
但是每周期内仅需两个采样，就能确定信号的最高频率
When you band-limit a signal, you eliminate all of the high frequency harmonics
当你对信号截频的时候，你也就截去了高于此频率的方波谐波信息
that could define a square wave with greater detail than this.
Now before you cry foul that this is creating detail where there shouldn’t be detail,
现在为防止各位在不应有细节的地方无中生有
just remember that your hearing is just as bandlimited as the output of the low-pass filter.
记住，你所听到的信号和低通滤波器输出的信号一样，都截频了
And also keep in mind that the whole chain here is messy.
还有一件事，整个过程是复杂混乱的
Everything in nature will oscillate with a sudden impulse of energy.
自然界的万物都会因能量的瞬息变化而突变
Even if a true square wave were to burst on the scene,
就算有一个方波突然出现
your eardrums will oscillate between the peaks in energy,
你的耳膜也是在能量的峰谷之间震动
注：而来回振动真需要时间啊
sort of like the wiggly wobblies in this bandlimited waveform.
有点像截频信号上的小波纹
So they key here is, don’t worry about it!
所以说，我们不要考虑这个了
This drove me crazy for days but the fact is, this is just how sound waves and nature work.
虽然这曾经让我很迷惑，但实际上，声波和大自然就这德行
Any signal can be represented as a sum of sine waves,
任意信号可用一系列正弦波合成
and bandlimiting it simply forces these oscillations into existence.
而截频也就是信号上波纹的来源了
The most pressing issue with this representation is that
这样的表示有一个问题
it can create ringing artifacts as a result of the Gibb’s phenomenon.
也就是由吉布斯现象搞出来的振铃效应
振铃效应：出现在信号快速转换时，附加在转换边缘上导致失真的信号
各位可在各种表情包的边缘上看到这种现象，也就是边缘的模糊
But now we’re getting into really nitpicky stuff,
不过马上要说的东西就要困难许多了
and you could easily argue that this would happen even in analog systems
你也能想到，这也能在模拟信号系统上出现
due once again, to natural oscillations. Either in the physical realm,
还是因为自然界的不确定性，在力学方面
such as the fact that both a phonograph needle and loudspeaker driver have mass
比如说，唱针和扬声器驱动单元都有质量的，无法立刻震动
and thus cannot move instantaneously,
So they will oscillate at their own harmonic frequency
这样，他们就有自己的谐波频率了
and create their own ringing artifacts anyway.
And also the electrical realm because the nature of any circuit will have some oscillations, too.
显然，在电学领域中，任何电路都有一些谐波的
So again, don’t worry about it.
所以，我们不必考虑
Now comes the part that sounds crazy but is completely true,
接下来你将听到的将会颠覆你的认知
and I can show it to you in a moment.
一会我来演示一下
Nyquist-shannon tells us that if we simply have twice the number of samples per second
由采样原理知，我们仅需按原信号限制频率的两倍频率采样
as the frequency of our signal’s band limit,
the exact bandlimited signal can be reproduced perfectly.
该带宽受限信号就可从采样中完美复现
And I mean, literally perfectly, using only those samples.
真的，就靠这些采样就行哦
This is admittedly weird, so let’s talk through it.
绝对有点奇怪，接着听介绍吧
Imagine an ADC is recording a sound. Every 40 thousandth of a second
现在模数转换器正在录音，每四万分之一秒
it takes an instantaneous reading of the signal it receives.
它记录下接收信号的瞬时状态
By quantifying it on a digital scale of our choosing,
再按照我们规定的量度量化之
it creates 40 thousand discrete samples every second.
（每秒钟）就能产生四万个离散采样
But remember, that signal has passed through a low-pass filter before it reached the ADC,
但是呢，信号在经过模数转换器前已经被低通滤波器截频了
so it does not contain any frequencies above 20 kilohertz.
所以（采样中）不可能有高于20kHz的信息
The truly mind-blowing part about Nyquist-Shannon is that
采样定理最惊人的地方在于
the samples we get from this bandlimited signal can ONLY reproduce the original signal.
由原来的截频信号产生的采样只能还原为原来的信号
There is only ONE signal that can possibly produce
只有那一个信号才有可能让ADC产生那一系列的采样
the exact series of samples that the ADC recorded.
当然，任意信号都可以产出很多不同组合的采样
然而，这些采样组合都只能表示这一个信号
Again, this is because we are dealing with a bandlimit.
当然，这些信号都是被截频的
Without a bandlimit in place, the samples could be defining parts of other strange waveforms
要没设置限制频率的话，由于混叠效应，采样就会被恢复成
due to aliasing, but when adhering to this bandlimit,
某种奇怪的波形，不过要是按照限制频率恢复的话
the resulting string of samples can only define exactly one waveform,
那一系列的采样就只能恢复成一种波形了
There is literally only one mathematical solution for the bandlimited waveform
对于限频信号来说，在数学上真的只有一个解能够满足这些采样
that would pass through all samples.
(Mind blow)
SuperBart:软件工程专业学这些吗？
This is some complicated stuff here, But just know that
虽然讲起来真复杂，但你仅需知道
if I have any series of samples, and I assume these are representing a bandlimited signal,
仅需一系列的采样，而且假定这些采样仅代表一个截频信号
then they can only possibly satisfy one waveform.
他们就只能满足一个波形了
And that, ladies and gentlemen, is why the myth that digital sound
所以，这就是数码音频输出的是类似阶梯信号的说法为啥是错的
creates a stair step pattern in the output is false.
But the weirder bit is that the DAC very well might.
然而有点疑惑的是，数模转换器很有可能会这样做
But before you freak out, that doesn’t mean
但在惊讶之前，先听我一言，这并不意味着
any stair-steppy signal has ever come out of a DAC or CD player or anything,
任何类似阶梯的信号会从数模转换器或CD播放器中输出
And that’s because of the same low-pass filter that originally bandlimited the input signal,
这都是和限制输入信号频率相同的低通滤波器的作用
Many digital to analog converters are actually quite simple. They use a resistor ladder,
很多数模转换器的原理真的很简单，他们使用了电阻网络
which is tied to the actual bits in each discrete sample, to produce the appropriate voltage.
他们根据每一位离散采样，产生相对应的电压
I don’t want to go on too much of a tangent here,
这里我不想深入太多
but they are really neat and explain how the simplest DACs work.
但是这就是简单的数模转换器的工作原理
Each bit of the sample is tied to a resistor.
每一位采样都与一个电阻元件相对应
If it’s a one, the resistor is activated and passes voltage through it.
要是“1”的话，电阻元件被激活，电压从其中穿过
And if it’s a zero, the resistor is not.
要是“0”的话，电阻元件就不会被激活
The network of resistors will create a unique voltage for
而电阻网络将会根据一系列采样的组合产生一独特的电压，因此
each possible combination of bits, and thus
you now end up with zeros and ones equalling a voltage of however specific you want.
你可以将一大堆数字信息转换成对应的电压还是啥的
A 16 bit DAC, like those used in the Compact Disc standard
用于激光唱片的16位数模转换器
(most of the time--we’ll get to that)
（用HDCD，SACD啥的hifi党给我找三门峡的水电去）
注: 各位有96/24资源的观众，看下频谱图，经常高于20kHz的地方就没信号了
will have 16 resistors, each controlled by one bit of the datastream.
有16个电阻元件，分别由一位数据流控制
These feed into intermediary resistors to create all of the possible voltages,
他们产生的电压传入中继电阻元件，以产生各种可能的电压
But the more bits you add, the more accurate these resistors have to become,
当然，更多位数，结果就会更精确
which helps explain why the earliest DACs were very expensive.
这也就是为啥早期的数模转换器十分昂贵了
The technology to produce resistors in an integrated circuit
在集成电路上制作该电阻元件的误差最多0.000015%
within an accuracy within approximately .000015%, was expensive for a while,
对于当时的科技水平来说，成本是昂贵的
Anyway, these R-2R DACs, as they’re sometimes called,
无论如何，这些R-2R电阻网络数模转换器
will produce a stair-step waveform from the output of the resistor ladder.
在电阻网络输出端会产生类似阶梯的波形信号
This is what’s called sample-and-hold.
这被叫做“取样保持”
Each sample sustains the given voltage level until the next sample is received by the DAC.
在下一采样到达数模转换器之前，电压会保持上一采样对应电压值
This had led to many, many, far too many people believing that this is the signal that
而这就是为啥很多人误认为这个信号
comes out of your CD player and goes into your amplifier.
就是从CD播放器输出到放大器的信号的原因了
It is easy to imagine this blocky-looking waveform screwing around
大家都能想到这玩意承载着贝九交响曲的音频信号啊
注：索尼副总裁大贺典雄建议光盘能容纳74分钟的音乐
也就是富特文格勒在1951年指挥的贝九交响曲的长度（当时已知最长的版本）
with your favorite recording of Beethoven’s 9th.
But you forget, dear audiophile, that the stair-steppy waveform
但是，有一点你们没注意到，这个类似阶梯的波形
will pass through a low-pass filter on its way out.
得过一遍低通滤波器截频
And that filter will create the same bandlimit on the output from the DAC,
这样数模转换器输出波形的最高频率
as was placed on the input of the ADC.
和输入进模数转换器波形的最高频率一样
Now, what this means, is that the output from the DAC is also bandlimited to 20 kilohertz.
也就是说，从数模转换器输出的波形也被截频到20kHz
And why does that matter? Because the very stair-steppy nature of the resistor ladder’s
为啥这很重要呢？因为这个类似阶梯的输出波形自身的
output is impossible with a bandlimit of 20 kilohertz.
最高频率不仅仅是20kHz那么低
Just like our square wave example, these vertical components require infinite bandwidth.
就跟方波一样，垂直部分的信号需要无限大的带宽才能承载
Good luck with that.
也许Farnsworth博士有这技术吧
But what’s even weirder, and kinda difficult to grasp, is that
而更奇怪的是，也是更难明白的是
because the output of the DAC has the same bandlimit as the ADC did,
由于从数模转换器输出信号的最高频率和
now we are dealing with Nyquist-Shannon again.
从模数转换器输出信号的最高频率相同，我们又要利用采样原理了
And the truly strange-but-true part of this, is that the only possible result of the output
而最奇怪的地方在于，从低通滤波器输出的信号
from the low pass filter is the original waveform that the ADC recorded.
只能是原先模数转换器录得的信号
Remember, with a bandlimited signal,
再说一遍，只要信号被截频
we can represent all of the detail within that signal with discrete samples,
仅需要将采样频率设为原信号最高频率的两倍
and with only a sample rate that is twice the bandlimit frequency.
我们就可以使用一系列离散采样来表示原信号所有的信息
If we create a waveform that passes through all of the samples,
若生成一满足所有采样的波形的话
then it must be the original waveform recorded by the ADC.
该波形一定是原先被模数转换器捕捉到的波形
The fact that the waveform comes out of the resistor ladder all choppy-like doesn’t
实际上，从电阻网络输出的类阶梯信号的垂直部分
matter in the slightest, because the low pass filter will bandlimit it and get rid of the
一点都不重要，因为经低通滤波器截频，垂直部分就会消失
choppies, Now it can only contain frequencies of 20 kilohertz or below.
现在信号只包含低于20kHz的部分了
Remember, the vertical parts of the stair-step pattern are impossible with that bandlimit,
记住，类阶梯信号中的垂直部分在截频后，是不存在的
so they just get smoothed out.
他们都会是很平滑的
And since we know that the DAC was outputting the correct voltage level with each sample,
而且数模转换器按照每一位采样，输出的电压是准确的
all of the samples must have been satisfied.
波形一定是满足每一采样的
Which means that after the LPF smooths the waveform,
也就是在低通滤波器平滑了波形后，波形一定是满足所有采样的
it must have passed through all of the samples.
And because there’s a bandlimit in place,
由于之前信号就是被截频的
Nyquist-Shannon proves that the output signal is the exact same one as the input.
根据采样原理，输出的信号和当时输入的信号绝对是相同的
To provide some evidence to back this claim up, take a look at this CD player.
为证明以上推论，我拿来了这个1993年索尼生产的CD换碟机
This is a Sony CD changer from 1993.
It has a relatively rudimentary DAC in part because it’s a cheaper machine
它有一个十分基础的数模转换器，因为这台机器廉价，而且陈旧
and in part because it’s older.
Let’s hook an oscilloscope up to it and take a look at the output coming from its RCA jacks,
现在我们把RCA输出的信号接到示波器上看看吧
This is just some music it’s playing right now.
目前正在播放一些音乐
Notice that there’s nothing in here that looks remotely stair-steppy.
我们注意到信号上没有任何垂直的部分
But let’s take it even further, I’ve created a CD with various tones generated in Audacity.
为了继续探索，我合成了一些波形，并将其刻在CD上
Let’s start with a 1 kilohertz square wave.
现在是1kHz方波
Even though in Audacity the samples look like this:
就算在Audacity上，也长这样
straight up, then hold, with a completely straight line between peaks,
电压直接提升，然后维持这样，最值之间就是一条直线
the output from the CD player is that wiggly wavy thing.
然而CD播放器的输出却有波纹
That happens because those wiggly wavies are the only way to make this square wave
这是因为在20kHz的限制频率下，方波只能长这样
with a 20 kilohertz bandlimit, and the wiggly bits are passing through each of those samples,
而该波纹信号正好能满足每一个采样
Now let’s switch to some sine waves. This is again 1 kilohertz.
现在，我们使用一些正弦波，先是1kHz的
This looks perfectly smooth, no stair-steps to be seen.
看上去十分平滑，没有垂直部分
To be fair, though, even in Audacity it looks pretty good.
说真的，在Audacity下看也很完美
Let’s move up to a 10 kilohertz sine wave. Now in Audacity it looks really gnarly,
现在我们用10kHz的正弦波，这会在Audacity下就很难看了
with the connections between the samples making a barely intelligible wave.
直接在各采样之间连线，很难让人觉得这玩意是个正弦波
There aren’t even 5 samples per cycle,
这玩意甚至都不是每循环5个采样
so how can the smooth detail of the sine wave possibly be reproduced?
那么，平滑的正弦波是怎么由此产生的呢？
Well, take a look! There’s a perfectly smooth sine wave for you, right there.
现在来看看，这里居然生成了如此平滑的正弦波诶
This is why some of you cringed when I drew straight lines between the samples.
这就是为什么有些人在我直接在采样连线时，故意说我错了
That’s only sort of what happens, and even then it’s not that accurate.
大略上是这样，可连这都不算很准确的示范
But it does serve as a sort of blend between the two realities.
但这毕竟是将模拟和数字给联系起来了啊
There is a stair-step pattern in the intermediate between the resistor ladder
确实，在电阻网格和低通滤波器之间确实有类阶梯波形
and the low pass filter. So the DAC does connect the dots, but like this.
所以数模转换器连接采样的方式是这样的
Then the LPF smooths out the connections between the dots,
然后低通滤波器将该波形平滑化
but that only happens as a side-effect of the fact that it’s creating a bandlimit.
但信号的平滑只是其将波形截频的一个副作用罢了
So the high frequency components, that’s the vertical parts here, get tossed out.
所以高频波形部分，也就是这里的垂直部分，全部消失了
What you’re left with is the only possible waveform that can both hit all the samples,
所产生的波形也只能是能满足所有采样的波形了
and which does not contain requency components above Nyquist. Simple, right?
也不包括高于奈奎斯特频率的信号了。真是好理解啊:-P
Ah! We haven’t even really talked about the CD itself yet!
完了，我还没说到激光唱片本身呢:-P
And this is pushing into the 14 or 15 minute mark already,
刚讲的东西，如果我在台本注释中没写错的话，已经14-15分钟了
if my gauge of time per written page is at all correct.
真.时间管理大师
OK, I guess we’re going to push the technology of the CD into another video.
好吧，也许下期视频我们再说CD科技的视频吧
But that’s OK, since we covered what makes sound out of numbers.
不过也还好，我们已经说过数码音频了
注：还没看上期视频的，快点去补课去！
And hopefully we’ve destroyed the myth that digital audio cannot produce smooth waveforms.
希望本期视频也能让大家知道，数码音频是能产生光滑波形的
It does,
就是可以（坚信）
Much of the information from this video (and indeed some selected clips) came from
本视频中提到的许多东西（以及一些片段）
注：xiph基金会就是开发FLAC和ogg编码器的组织
a lovely video by Monty at xiph,org. I’ve linked to a great article of his down below,
是参考了xiph的Monty工程师的视频，文章链接附下
and a card will pop up now heading to his video.
文章中附带了一个视频
SuperBart：该视频已经被搬运到Bilibili了，故只有视频链接附下
Many, many people brought this to my attention on Twitter and elsewhere, so thank you.
很多人向我推荐了这个视频，十分感谢
He’s got some much better demonstrations than I do that cover this topic.
在我准备这个话题时，他提供了很多更好的示例
He also explains why the bit depth affects noise, and not clarity,
他还解释了位深对噪音的影响，并含糊地指出
what dithering is and how it reduces quantization noise, and much more.
什么是抖动，它是如何减少量化噪声的，还有更多
But I will give you one last tid-bit before I sign off.
但在视频结束前，我要再说一件事
You may have noticed that in the video we’ve been discussing
你也许注意到，我在视频中讨论的是
a theoretical sampling rate of 40 kHz, as this Nyquist sampling rate
理论奈奎斯特采样率，也就是40kHz
could perfectly capture all of what human hearing can pick up.
该频率正好把我们听力范围内的音频信息都采集了下来
But the CD standard’s sampling rate is 44.1 kilohertz.
但激光唱片的采样率为44.1kHz
Why the extra 4.1? That seems awfully specific.
为啥非得多4.1kHz呢，显得过于做作
Well, that’s due to the fact that low-pass filters aren’t perfect.
这是因为低通滤波器不是完美的
They can’t just cut off frequencies above a point,
它不能直接把高于限制频率的信息直接删掉
they instead have a transition window where the frequencies degrade to zero,
低通滤波器
目标限制频率
而是设置了一个过渡区间，将高于限制频率以上的信息降至零
过渡区间
The 44,1 kilohertz sampling rate is to accommodate for that window.
44.1kHz的采样率就是为了适应这个过渡区间
Without a hard-cut on the low-pass filter, aliasing could occur
如果低通滤波器不是一刀去信号的话，混叠现象就会发生
because the samples might define a waveform of a higher frequency than Nyquist.
因为采样也许会无中生出个高于奈奎斯特频率的波形
This is a precisely why we need an LPF.
而混叠现象就是我们需要低通滤波器的原因了
Both of these waveforms satisfy all the samples,
这两个正弦波全部满足所有的采样点
so to prevent one of them from coming through, we need to decide a limit in frequency.
为防止其中一个输出，我们需要限制频率
If the red waveform is above the Nyquist limit, then it won’t get reproduced.
若红色波形高于奈奎斯特频率的话，该波形就不会被生成
But if the low-pass filter could let slip some signals above our decided sample rate,
但如果低通滤波器不小心放过了一些高于限制频率的信号的话
scenarios like this might occur.
这种情况就会发生
Therefore, the sample rate was chosen to be 44,1 kilohertz,
所以，将采样率限制为44.1kHz的话
that way it exceeds the transition window for our desired 20 kilohertz cutoff.
就会包括超过20kHz过渡区间内的信号了
And by sampling a bit beyond the audible range, we don’t have to worry about
采样率只需稍微超过人耳的听力范围
spurious aliasing artifacts from samples in the transition band.
就不必担心过渡带上的信号导致的混叠效应了
But the more interesting thing about the 44,1 kilohertz rate
SuperBart: 没完了是吗:-P
但对于44.1kHz，更有意思的是
is that it was also chosen for easy digital sound storage before a CD gets pressed.
这是在激光唱片上市前就被确定的数码音频采样率
This was the perfect sampling rate for storing sound
对于NTSC制式和PAL制式的录音带来说
on both an NTSC and a PAL U-Matic videocassette recorder.
用这个采样率存储光盘是再好不过了
The commercial VCR format from Sony was among the earliest ways to
索尼生产的商用VCR是最早用来存储数码音频的格式之一
store a digital audio stream, using the video signal sort of like a giant QR code.
使用视频信号存储，有点像很大的二维码
It’s not literally being read in that sense,
当然，直接放磁带你也看不懂
but the data is stored on the tape as a field of black and white bars in each line,
但是存储在磁带上的数据就是一帧帧黑白条带
so if watching the output on-screen it would look like a flashing screen of
所以，要是将磁带直接播放的话，视频输出就像是一张张
QR codes whizzing by 60 times per second, 44,1 kHz would, on both NTSC and PAL signals,
二维码在以60帧每秒的刷新率闪烁，根据NTSC和PAL信号刷新率
work out to 3 samples per video line.
就是44.1kHz，也就是每条扫描线包含三个采样
So in a strange twist, the world of analog video dicated how digital sound would work.
有点奇怪吧，模拟视频竟和数字音频有着不解之缘
Thanks for watching, I hope you enjoyed the video,
感谢收看，希望大家喜欢！
翻译：SuperBart@Bilibili
原作者发布于2018年8月10日
本系列视频下期预告：CD的介绍
As I end all of my videos apparently,
在每期视频的最后
if this is your first time coming across the channel
若你是头一回看到他的频道
and you liked what you saw, please consider subscribing.
而且你喜欢的话，考虑去油管关注一下
Also, and I know this can sound weird,
还有，虽然这听上去很奇怪
but for those that follow my videos,
但对于关注我的人们
you might want to make sure you are actually subscribed
你也许应该检查一下你是否真订阅了
Often times YouTube just serves you content because
有时油管只是给你推荐我的视频
it knows you like it, and you might think
因为你喜欢看，然后你就认为
you are subscribed when you aren’t.
你订阅了，然而你并没有
Same goes for all channels, really.
对于其他频道同理
But I’ll be the selfish one today and post this reminder,
但今天我自私一下，给大家提醒一下
As always, thank you to everyone who
当然，感谢那些在Patreon上支持我的人
supports this channel on Patreon,
especially the fine folks who are scrolling up your screen.
尤其是左侧滚动字幕中的人
Supporters on Patreon have turned my weird hobby of
支持者们的赞助让我把做古怪科技
making videos about technology into a job,
视频的爱好变成了一份工作
and you all deserve my thanks.
十分感谢你们
If you would like to pledge some support
如果你想提供一些支持并帮助这个频道
and help the channel grow, please check out my Patreon page,
发展的话，可以去原作者的Patreon页面
Thanks for your consideration, and I’ll see you next time!
感谢您的支持，下期视频再见！